Finding Aid for the Collection of Broadside Ballads from England, Ireland, and the United States LSC.0605
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collection of Broadside Ballads from England, Ireland, and the United States
1798-1899
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0605
5.0 linear feet (10 boxes and 1 flat box)
Broadside ballads provided lyrics to popular songs, and were sold cheaply on individual sheets of paper. This collection contains approximately 2,000 English, Irish, and American broadsides from the nineteenth century.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. See the Existence and Location of Copies note for the link to the digitized materials.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942327303606533
History
Broadside ballads provided lyrics to popular songs, and were sold cheaply on individual sheets of paper. While the lyrics were often new, the tunes would have been familiar to all. As a widely circulating form of popular literature, ballads can be a useful resource for the study of the history of literacy and can also be of interest to those studying the history of printing. Ballads traditionally addressed themes from everyday experience in both urban and rural communities. They thus provide important source material for social history and the history of popular culture.
Scope and Content
This collection contains approximately 2,000 English, Irish, and American broadsides from the nineteenth century, including a large number of broadsides from the Catnach Press as well as some from women printers (especially Anne Ryle and Elizabeth Hodges, with a few by Ann Birt). Many of the ballads in this collection deal with common issues in family life, including courtship and marriage, domestic disputes, and the departure and return of young sailors. The collection includes examples of drinking songs, love songs, and patriotic songs. It offers many variants of traditional favorites, such as "Lannigan's Ball" and "John Barleycorn". The collection also represents ballads as sources of information and commentary on current events of local, national and international significance. Of the holdings in English ballads, many report on wars, economic conditions, and the activities of the monarchy. Land tenure, the Fenians, and other protests of English rule feature prominently in the collection's Irish ballads. A major theme of the American ballads is the Civil War (1861-1865).
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
England, 1750-ca. 1899 (6 boxes)
Ireland, ca. 1828-1869 (2 boxes)
United States, ca. 1824-1887 (2 boxes).
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Broadside Ballads from England, Ireland, and the United States (5 items).
Broadside poems.; Ballads, English -- United States -- 19th century.; Ballads, English -- Great Britain -- 19th century.; Catnach Press
- England
  - Agg, John, 1798
    Scope and Contents note
    Printed in Evesham, England.
    - Cotswold volunteers. The Cotswold volunteers. Evesham, England; Agg, printer, Evesham, 1798., Shelfmark: 1; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 32 × 20 cm. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ainsley, W., ca. 1841-1860
    Printed in Durham, England.
    - Angel's whisper. The banks of Allan Water. Woman. Lover, Samuel, 1797-1868, The angel's whisper. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 2; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 3 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Angel's whisper. The banks of Allan Water. Woman. Lewis, M. G. (Matthew Gregory), 1775-1818, The banks of Allan Water. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 2; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 3 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Angel's whisper. The banks of Allan Water. Woman. Wither, George, 1588-1667, Woman. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 2; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 3 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Death of Nelson. The monks of old. Old Towler. Old Towler. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 3; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Death of Nelson. The monks of old. Old Towler. The monks of old. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 3; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Death of Nelson. The monks of old. Old Towler. Arnold, Samuel James, 1774-1852, The death of Nelson. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 3; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ivy green. The mill's merry sail. My father's old farm. My father's old farm. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): ill. (wood engraving); cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ivy green. The mill's merry sail. My father's old farm. Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870, The ivy green. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): ill. (wood engraving); cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ivy green. The mill's merry sail. My father's old farm. The mill's merry sail. Durham, England; W. Ainsley, Printer, Durham, [between 1841 and 1860]., Shelfmark: 4; 1 sheet ([1] p.): ill. (wood engraving); cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Angus, M., 1804
    Printed in Newcastle, England.
    - Bob Cranky's 'size Sunday. Selkirk, John, Bob Cranky's 'size Sunday. Newcastle, England; M. Angus and Son, Printers, 1804., Shelfmark: 5; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 34 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Aston, 1824
    Printed in Manchester, England.
    - New comic song, taken from Tim Bobbin's popular story of "Tummus & Meary," giving a full, true and particular account of his misfortunes on his journey to Rochdale, to sell th' wye Kawve ant' keaw. A new comic song, taken from Tim Bobbin's popular story of "Tummus & Meary," giving a full, true and particular account of his misfortunes on his journey to Rochdale, to sell th' wye Kawve ant' keaw. Manchester, England; Aston, Printer, Manchester, 1824., Shelfmark: 6; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 15 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Barr, R., ca. 1840-1852
    Printed in Leeds, England.
    - Beautiful child. Young Edward the gallant Hussar. Watson, J. W. (John Whittaker), 1824-1890, Beautiful child. Leeds, England; Barr, Printer, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 7; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Beautiful child. Young Edward the gallant Hussar. Young Edward the gallant Hussar. Leeds, England; Barr, Printer, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 7; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ben Bolt. Jack & Susan, and long life to Sir Chas. Napier. Ben's reply. Ben's reply. Leeds, England; R. Barr, Printer, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 17 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ben Bolt. Jack & Susan, and long life to Sir Chas. Napier. Ben's reply. Dawson, Samuel, Jack & Susan, and long life to Sir Chas. Napier. Leeds, England; R. Barr, Printer, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 17 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ben Bolt. Jack & Susan, and long life to Sir Chas. Napier. Ben's reply. English, Thomas Dunn, 1819-1902, Ben Bolt. Leeds, England; R. Barr, Printer, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 8; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 17 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Deeds of Napoleon. Gossiping wife. Gossiping wife. Leeds, England; Barr, Printer, 58 Meadow Lane, Holbeck, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 9; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Deeds of Napoleon. Gossiping wife. The deeds of Napoleon. Leeds, England; Barr, Printer, 58 Meadow Lane, Holbeck, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 9; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Happy day. Invitation to Sunday schools. Happy day. Leeds, England; Sold by R. Barr, 72, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 10; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Happy day. Invitation to Sunday schools. Invitation to Sunday schools. Leeds, England; Sold by R. Barr, 72, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 10; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Mary's complaint. Heaven's my home. Heaven's my home. Leeds, England; Sold, wholesale and retail, by R. Barr, 72, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 11; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Mary's complaint. Heaven's my home. Mary's complaint. Leeds, England; Sold, wholesale and retail, by R. Barr, 72, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 11; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - My gentle mother dear! Do you ever think of me love. Lover, Samuel, 1797-1868, My gentle mother dear!. Leeds, England; Barr, Printer, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - My gentle mother dear! Do you ever think of me love. Do you ever think of me love. Leeds, England; Barr, Printer, Marsh Lane, Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 12; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - One thing or t'other. The green mossy banks of the Lea. Gypsey boy. The Englishman. Gypsey boy. Leeds, England; R. Barr, Printer, Marsh-lane, Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 13; 1 sheet ([2] p.): 3 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 12 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - One thing or t'other. The green mossy banks of the Lea. Gypsey boy. The Englishman. The green mossy banks of the Lea. Leeds, England; R. Barr, Printer, Marsh-lane, Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 13; 1 sheet ([2] p.): 3 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 12 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - One thing or t'other. The green mossy banks of the Lea. Gypsey boy. The Englishman. One thing or t'other. Leeds, England; R. Barr, Printer, Marsh-lane, Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 13; 1 sheet ([2] p.): 3 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 12 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - One thing or t'other. The green mossy banks of the Lea. Gypsey boy. The Englishman. Cook, Eliza, 1818-1889, The Englishman. Leeds, England; R. Barr, Printer, Marsh-lane, Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 13; 1 sheet ([2] p.): 3 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 12 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Queer doings in China! Hancock, Edward, Queer doings in China!. Leeds, England; Barr Printer 14 Marsh Lane Leeds, [ca. 1840]., Shelfmark: 14; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 3 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 18 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ranter's ship. On the cross! On the cross!. Leeds, England; Sold by R. Barr, Tobacconist, Dealer in Snuff & Cigars, 72, Marsh-lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 15; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ranter's ship. On the cross! The ranters' ship. Leeds, England; Sold by R. Barr, Tobacconist, Dealer in Snuff & Cigars, 72, Marsh-lane, Leeds, [ca. 1852]., Shelfmark: 15; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bass, D., 18--
    - Awkward recruit. Awkward recruit. Newcastle, England; Printed by D, Bass, Newcastle, [18--]., Shelfmark: 16; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Batchelar family, ca. 1828-1842
    Includes imprints by Daniel Batchelor and Thomas Batchelor, London, England.
    - Ben Backstay, the boatswain. Jack Robinson. Dibdin, Charles, 1745-1814, Ben Backstay, the boatswain. London, England; Batchelar, Printer, Hackney Road Crescent, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 17; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Ben Backstay, the boatswain. Jack Robinson. Hudson, Thomas, Jack Robinson. London, England; Batchelar, Printer, Hackney Road Crescent, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 17; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Curly-headed ploughboy The curly-headed ploughboy. London, England; Batchelar, Printer, opposite the Refuge for the Destitute, Hackney Road, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 18; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 12 × 8 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Flowers of Edinburgh. Auld landsyne [sic]. D'Urfey, Thomas, 1653-1723, Flowers of Edinburgh. London, England; Printed by T. Batchelar, 14, Hackney Road Crescent, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 19; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 11 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Flowers of Edinburgh. Auld landsyne [sic]. Burns, Robert, 1759-1796, Auld langsyne [sic]. London, England; Printed by T. Batchelar, 14, Hackney Road Crescent, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 19; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 11 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Merry days of old. Jefferys, Charles, 1807-1865, The merry days of old. London, England; Printed and sold by D. Batchelar, 14, Hackney Road Cresent, opposite the Refuge for the Destitute, Hackney Road, near Shoreditch, London, [between 1836 and 1842]., Shelfmark: 20; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 16 × 8 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Old yew. Merry sunshine. Gentle moonlight. Gentle moonlight. London, England; Printed by D. Batchelar, 14, Hackney Road Cresent, near Shoreditch, London, [between 1836 and 1842]., Shelfmark: 21; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Old yew. Merry sunshine. Gentle moonlight. Merry sunshine. London, England; Printed by D. Batchelar, 14, Hackney Road Cresent, near Shoreditch, London, [between 1836 and 1842]., Shelfmark: 21; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Old yew. Merry sunshine. Gentle moonlight. The old yew-tree. London, England; Printed by D. Batchelar, 14, Hackney Road Cresent, near Shoreditch, London, [between 1836 and 1842]., Shelfmark: 21; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Poor little fisherma[n]'s girl. The fate of young Henry, in answer to "Caroline of Edinboro' Town". The fate of young Henry, in answer to "Caroline of Edinboro' Town". London, England; Printed and sold by T. Batchelar, opposite the Refuge, Hackney Road, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 22; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 24 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Poor little fisherma[n]'s girl. The fate of young Henry, in answer to "Caroline of Edinboro' Town". The poor little fisherma[n]'s girl. London, England; Printed and sold by T. Batchelar, opposite the Refuge, Hackney Road, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 22; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 24 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Richard of Taunton Dean. Dumble dum deary. Dumble dum deary. London, England; Printed and sold by T. Batchelar, opposite the Refuge, Hackney Road, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 23; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Richard of Taunton Dean. Dumble dum deary. Richard of Taunton Dean. London, England; Printed and sold by T. Batchelar, opposite the Refuge, Hackney Road, [between 1828 and 1832]., Shelfmark: 23; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sally Sly. Cab, cab. Sally Sly. London, England; Printed and sold by D. Batchelar, at his old established Toy Warehouse, Hackney Road, [between 1836 and 1842]., Shelfmark: 24; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sally Sly. Cab, cab. Cab, cab. London, England; Printed and sold by D. Batchelar, at his old established Toy Warehouse, Hackney Road, [between 1836 and 1842]., Shelfmark: 24; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Trab, trab. My Rosette dear. My Rosette dear. London, England; Printed and sold by D. Batchelar, 14, Hackney Road Crescent, near Shoreditch, [between 1836 and 1842]., Shelfmark: 25; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Trab, trab. My Rosette dear. Trab, trab. London, England; Printed and sold by D. Batchelar, 14, Hackney Road Crescent, near Shoreditch, [between 1836 and 1842]., Shelfmark: 25; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 2 ill. (wood engravings); 26 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bebbington, J. O., ca. 1850-1861
    - Great sea snake. The green mossy banks of the Lea. The green mossy banks of the Lea. Manchester, England; [Bebbington], Printer, [26 Goulden-street,] Oldham Road, Manchester, [and sold by…], [ca. 1850-1861]., Shelfmark: 26; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Great sea snake. The green mossy banks of the Lea. Holcroft, Thomas, 1745-1809, The great sea snake. Manchester, England; [Bebbington], Printer, [26 Goulden-street,] Oldham Road, Manchester, [and sold by…], [ca. 1850-1861]., Shelfmark: 26; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 26 × 20 cm. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Sunshine after rain. Suit of corduroy. The ivy green. Suit of corduroy. Manchester, England; [Bebbington], Printer, [26 Goulden-street,] Oldham Road, Manchester, [and sold by…], [ca. 1850-1861]., Shelfmark: 27; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Sunshine after rain. Suit of corduroy. The ivy green. Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870, The ivy green. Manchester, England; [Bebbington], Printer, [26 Goulden-street,] Oldham Road, Manchester, [and sold by…], [ca. 1850-1861]., Shelfmark: 27; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Sunshine after rain. Suit of corduroy. The ivy green. Sunshine after rain. Manchester, England; [Bebbington], Printer, [26 Goulden-street,] Oldham Road, Manchester, [and sold by…], [ca. 1850-1861]., Shelfmark: 27; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 19 cm. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Birt family (Appeal-Bung), ca. 1828-1851
    Printed in London, England.
    - Answer to Burns' Lovely Jean. The answer to Burns' Lovely Jean. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St Andrew- Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 29; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Answer to Isabelle. The lass of Richmond Hill. MacNally, Leonard, 1752-1820, The lass of Richmond Hill. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St Andrew- Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 30; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Answer to Isabelle. The lass of Richmond Hill. Answer to Isabelle. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St Andrew- Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 30; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Answer to Sweet home. Answer to Sweet home. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, Wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street Seven Dials London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 31; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 9 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Answer to The garden gate. Answer to The garden gate. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 32; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 9 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Anti-teetotalers song: or, Beer versus water. The anti-teetotalers song: or, Beer versus water. London, England; Birt, Printer, 39, Great St. Andrdw [sic] Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1833 and 1851]., Shelfmark: 33; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 18 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Appeal to the benevolent. An appeal to the benevolent. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 28; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 9 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Banks of the Band. The banks of Band. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 34; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 9 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Behold how brightly breaks the morn. Kenney, James, 1780-1849, Behold how brightly breaks the morn. London, England; Printed by T. Birt wholesale and retail, 10, Great St Andrew-Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 35; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Betsy of Dundee. Betsy of Dundee. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew Street. Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 36; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Beware of the Pope!! Beware of the Pope!!. London, England; Birt, Printer, 39, Great St. Andrew Street, Seven Dials, [between 1833 and 1851]., Shelfmark: 37; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 20 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Billy O'Rooke. Billy O'Rooke. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, (wholesale and retail) 10, Great St. Andrew-Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 38; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Blue bonnets are over the border. Great flopping bonnets are now all the order. Great flopping bonnets are now all the order. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 39; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Blue bonnets are over the border. Great flopping bonnets are now all the order. Scott, Walter, Sir, 1771-1832, The blue bonnets are over the border. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 39; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bonny moon. Hurrah for the bonnets of blue. Burns, Robert, 1759-1796, Hurrah for the bonnets of blue. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great st. Andrew-Street Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 40; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bonny moon. Hurrah for the bonnets of blue. Bonny moon. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great st. Andrew-Street Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 40; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Brown jug. Brown jug. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street Seven Dials London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 41; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 9 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bung your eye. Bung your eye. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 42; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Birt family (Castle-Colin), 1828-1829
    - Castle Hyde. Castle Hyde. London, England; Printed by T. Birt, wholesale and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 43; 1 sheet ([1] p.): 1 ill. (wood engraving); 25 × 9 cm. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Cherry ripe. My heart & lute. Herrick, Robert, 1591-1674, Cherry ripe. London, England; [Printed by T. Bir]t, [wholesale] and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 44; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Cherry ripe. My heart & lute. Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852, My heart & lute. London, England; [Printed by T. Bir]t, [wholesale] and retail, 10, Great St. Andrew-Street, Seven Dials, London, [between 1828 and 1829]., Shelfmark: 44; 1 sheet ([1] p.); 25 × 10 cm. (Box 3, Folder 11)